778.882.0318 christineliu0318@gmail.com

PROFILE

UBC Bachelor of Science graduate in Biology with strong foundation in fundamental research skills, including literature searches and data organization. I am a motivated and eager learner who is willing to dedicate the time to move your research forward. An excellent independent worker who is able to produce results within set deadlines with solution-oriented critical thinking.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Cell Biology and Genetics Specialization

2009-2014

University of British Columbia

- Cumulative GPA: 84%
- President's Entrance Scholarship, Sept 2009 (\$4000)
- Provincial Scholarship Award 2009 (\$1000)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Student Researcher for Dr. Orson Moritz, Eye Care Centre

Jan 2013-Apr 2013

- Animal husbandry, confocal microscopy
- Conducts genotyping qPCR, cryosection, immunofluorescence to characterize frog lines
- Maintained and established a genotype database of over 20 unique frog lines
- Skills developed: data organization, literature search, data analysis

Co-op Student Researcher for Dr. Emma Guns Lab, Vancouver Prostate Centre

April 2012-Dec 2012

- Isolated exosomes to investigate their effects on protein expression in recipient cells
- Organized and managed large quantities of data on Excel
- Skills developed: literature search, data entry, research presentation, critical thinking

NSERC USRA with Dr. Wasteneys, University of British Columbia

Jan 2011-Aug 2011

- Organized and performed analysis on large sets of data using Excel
- NSERC USRA project: Fluorescence microscopy of CesA6 in Arabidopsis thaliana
 - o Imaged and analyzed trajectories of CesA6 in YFP seedlings using spinning disk microscopy
 - o Processed images and tracked over 400 velocities of CesA6 particles using kymograph software on ImageJ
- Skills developed: data management, independent work ethic

PUBLICATIONS

Fujita M, Himmelspach R, Ward J, et al. The *anisotropy1* D604N mutation in the Arabidopsis cellulose synthase1 catalytic domain reduces cell wall crystallinity and the velocity of cellulose synthase complexes. *Plant Physiology*. 2013;162(1):74–85.

Published in conference proceedings:

Hosseini-Beheshti, E., Liu, C., Gao, T., and Tomlinson, Guns ES.

Prostate Cancer derived Exosomes could Promote Prostate Cancer Progression via Activation of the ERK Cell Signaling Path way. Published at the International Society for Extracellular vesicles (ISEV) 2013.

Hosseini-Beheshti, E., Liu, C., Adomat, H., (Tomlinson) Guns, ES. Investigation into the role of prostate cancer derived exosomes on their tumor microenvironment. Published at the American Association for Cancer Research Annual Meeting 2013.

VOLUNTEER AND OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Chiropractic Assistant, Jassal Chiropractic

August 2014-Present

- Responsible for clinic management: supplies documentation, book-keeping, maintaining accurate financial documentation
- Management of large databases of confidential data of over 300 patients
- Responsible for maintenance of clinic statistics
- Skills acquired: bookkeeping, multitasking, interpersonal skills

Marketing Assistant, UBC Student Recreation Centre

Sept 2013-Apr 2014

- Created, uploaded and maintained content to the UBC Student Recreation Wordpress website
- Distributed marketing materials around campus while driving large vehicles
- Skills acquired: time management, multitasking, Adobe Illustrator, problem solving

Training Officer for Division 426, St. John Ambulance

Sept 2011-Present

- Volunteer as a Medical First Responder at various community events in the Lower Mainland
- Training officer for all new members of the Richmond Division
- Lead and conceptualized weekly lesson plans for 20+ members.
- Skills developed: time management, independent work ethic, interpersonal skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- MS Word, MS Powerpoint, MS Excel Proficiency
- Certified Advanced Medical First Responder Level 1
- Biological and Chemical safety course certification
- Animal Ethics certification

- CPR and AED for Health Care Providers
- Valid Class 5 Driver License
- Bilingual Diploma (French and English)